Theta Delta Chi, Kappa Charge Records UA231
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Theta Delta Chi, Kappa Charge Records
1856 -- 2016
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Theta Delta Chi, Kappa Charge
UA231
0.8 Linear Feet 2 boxes
1 Web sites
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series: Theta Delta Chi records and memorabilia; and Web crawls.
Custodial History
The majority of this collection was compiled by Russell Miller as part of his "Activities and Organizations" collection (See UA024) with additional materials donated by Leonard F. Lombardi, Class of 1952.
Scope and Contents
This collections contains photographs, publications, memorabilia, correspondence, and web crawls related to the Theta Delta Chi Fraternity, Kappa Charge at Tufts.
Biographical / Historical
The Kappa Charge of Theta Delta Chi was founded at Tufts College in 1856 by Augustus E. Scott. Scott was a member of the Zeta Charge at Brown prior to entering the Class of 1858 at Tufts during his Sophomore year. Future Tufts College President Elmer H. Capen was also among the founding members of the fraternity. Kappa is the oldest Theta Delta Chi charge in continuous existence.
The Theta Delta Chi magazine, the "Shield," was revived at Tufts by Kappa charge members Edwin A. Start and E.W Powers.
In 1893, a house for the fraternity was erected at 123 Packard Avenue from design by the Boston architect, J.P.Rinn.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Student life; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations
- Theta Delta Chi records and memorabilia, 1856 -- 1980; UA231.001; 0.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This collections contains photographs, publications, memorabilia, and correspondence related to the Theta Delta Chi Fraternity, Kappa Charge at Tufts.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Convention invitations and programs, 1856 -- 1878; UA231.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, correspondence and financial documents, 1882 -- 1967; UA231.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Agreement of Association, 1883; UA231.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Meeting notice, 1883; UA231.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Class Day invitation, 1899; UA231.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Reunion invitation, 1900; UA231.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Patron Goddess of Theta Delta Chi (Minerva), 1900; UA231.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Theta Delta Chi House Architect Drawing, 1900 -- 1920; UA231.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1930 -- 1980; UA231.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Theta Delta Chi Pledge Card, 1949; UA231.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Theta Delta Chi Banner, 1950; UA231.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Theta Delta Chi Handbook, 1971; UA231.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2016; UA231.002; 1 Web sites
  Quarterly web crawls of the Theta Delta Chi - Kappa Charge website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - Theta Delta Chi - Kappa Charge, 2015 -- 2016; UA231.002.00001
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl. (Inactive)